<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Artifact Hub Blog</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Artifact Hub Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Embed Artifact Details On Your Site</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/embed-widget/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/embed-widget/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/embed-widget/embed.png" alt="Embedded Packages" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever want to show off a package from the Artifact Hub on a website? I know I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about putting one in the sidebar of a website. Artifact Hub now makes that easy with a widget you can embed. The above image displays various configurations of the widget you can get from Artifact Hub.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Verified Publishers and Official Status</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/verified-and-official-repos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/verified-and-official-repos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever wonder if you are getting a package for a piece of software from the developer of that software? Or, have you ever wondered if the person who listed a repository or package on the Artifact Hub owns it? If you have, than you&amp;rsquo;re in luck. The Artifact Hub has badges that can answer those questions for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Helm Values Schema Reference</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-values-schema-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-values-schema-reference/</guid><description>&lt;p>Helm v3 introduced &lt;a href="https://helm.sh/docs/topics/charts/#schema-files">schemas for values&lt;/a>. The schemas are written as JSON Schemas and put in a chart in a file named &lt;code>values.schema.json&lt;/code> that goes right alongside &lt;code>values.yaml&lt;/code> files. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if there was a way to easily use these files to understand the values in a chart? Artifact Hub provides just that with its Values Schema Reference.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Discover Tekton Tasks</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/discover-tekton-tasks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/discover-tekton-tasks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Artifact Hub has already provided search and discovery for Helm charts, OLM based operators, Falco rules, OPA policies, Tinkerbell actions, Krew (kubectl) plugins, and Helm plugins. These are all &lt;a href="https://www.cncf.io/">CNCF&lt;/a> project related artifacts. We are happy to share that we have expanded beyond the CNCF to support another non-profit foundation based project with support for &lt;a href="https://tekton.dev/">Tekton&lt;/a> tasks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Container Image Scanning</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/container-image-scanning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/container-image-scanning/</guid><description>&lt;p>When trying to make a decision about which artifacts to use it&amp;rsquo;s useful to know some information about the security of the artifact. With Artifact Hub, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to see security scans for container based artifacts such as Operator Framework OLM based operators, some Helm Charts, OPA Policies, and Tinkerbell actions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is The Artifact Hub?</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/what-is-artifacthub/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/what-is-artifacthub/</guid><description>Finding cloud native artifacts on the Internet can be difficult. When we talk about artifacts we mean things like Helm charts, Kubernetes operators, Falco rules, and Open Policy Agent (OPA) policies. If you use a search engine to look for them the results will be mixed with articles, documentation, and discussion. This experience is far from ideal if you want to find a package or tool to install.
This has lead to the rise of Hubs like the Helm Hub (which now redirects to the Artifact Hub) and Operator Hub.</description></item></channel></rss>