<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Artifact Hub Blog</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Artifact Hub Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Video: Discover, Analyze, and Share Cloud Native Artifacts</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/kubecon-na-24-video/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/kubecon-na-24-video/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=027rAkswODw">&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/kubecon-na-24-video/kubecon-video.png" alt="artifact hub kubecon video" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At KubeCon/CloudNativeCon 2024 in North America we presented an overview of Artifact Hub. It covered discovering artifacts, analyzing them, and sharing them. The video from this presentation is online and available &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=027rAkswODw">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Join Artifact Hub at KubeCon North America '24</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/kubecon-na-24/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/kubecon-na-24/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/kubecon-na-24/kubecon.png" alt="kubecon" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Artifact Hub has its &lt;a href="https://sched.co/1howN">first maintainer talk at KubeCon/CloudNativeCon in Salt Lake City&lt;/a>.
If you&amp;rsquo;re attending KubeCon and want to learn more about Artifact Hub, including how to add your artifacts to it, this is a session where you can learn about it. To quote the session abstract:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Incubation</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/incubation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 09:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/incubation/</guid><description>&lt;p>About 5 years ago, at CloudNativeCon + KubeCon North American &amp;lsquo;19 in San Diego, the idea for Artifact Hub began. At the time there were a few cloud native artifacts and they were discovered via general search or individual targeted sites like the now defunct Helm Hub. In 2020 the development on Artifact Hub began and it eventually moved to a point where we filed for Incubation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are happy to announce that Artifact Hub is now a CNCF Incubating Project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/incubation/cncf-projects.png" alt="CNCF Website screenshot for projects" />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artifact Statistics</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/artifact-statistics/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/artifact-statistics/</guid><description>&lt;p>Have you ever wondered how often an artifact is viewed on Artifact Hub? It&amp;rsquo;s possible to view these details right on the page for an artifact. The following image captures 30 days work of statistics for the &lt;a href="https://artifacthub.io/packages/helm/artifact-hub/artifact-hub">Artifact Hub chart&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/artifact-statistics/stats.png" />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Exploring Helm Named Templates</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-named-templates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-named-templates/</guid><description>&lt;p>Helm provides the ability to create &lt;a href="https://helm.sh/docs/chart_template_guide/named_templates/">named templates&lt;/a> in charts. You can use a named template one or more times and even pass argumnets to them. Named templates are a wonderful way to write reusable templates for your charts and the building block for &lt;a href="https://helm.sh/docs/topics/library_charts/#helm">library charts&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Artifact Hub now allows you to navigate the named templates from the template explorer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-named-templates/browser.png" />&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Comparing Helm Templates Between Versions</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-template-compare/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-template-compare/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-template-compare/diff.png" alt="A template diff for the Artifact Hub chart" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Have you ever wondered, what changed in the templates between two versions of a &lt;a href="https://helm.sh">Helm&lt;/a> chart? It&amp;rsquo;s possible to see this for charts listed on Artifact Hub.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Container Image Support</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/container-images/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/container-images/</guid><description>&lt;p>When containers took off in popularity, everyone was putting their container images meant for general public consumption on &lt;a href="https://hub.docker.com/">Docker Hub&lt;/a>. This made it easy to discover container images. You could search Docker Hub or use &lt;code>docker search&lt;/code> in your console.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With the rise of the &lt;a href="https://opencontainers.org/">Open Container Initiative (OCI)&lt;/a> and many different companies operating container registries this all changed. Images meant for public consumption could be in &lt;a href="https://ghcr.io">GitHub Container Registry&lt;/a>, the &lt;a href="https://gallery.ecr.aws/">Amazon ECR Public Gallery&lt;/a>, and many other registries. This change distributed where images were hosted.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Distributed images meant there was no longer a centralized search solution to look for container images. Discovery of images became more difficult.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, we are please to share that Artifact Hub now supports listing and searching for container images.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://artifacthub.io/packages/container/ah/ah">&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/container-images/ah.png" alt="The ah tool as an image listed on Artifact Hub" />&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Screenshots</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/screenshots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/screenshots/</guid><description>&lt;p>Does your application have a user interface? Would you want to display screenshots of it? If that&amp;rsquo;s the case, you can display them on Artifact Hub for Helm, OLM, Krew, and Tekton. The screenshot below shows the display screenshots for the &lt;a href="https://artifacthub.io/packages/helm/artifact-hub/artifact-hub">Artifact Hub chart&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/screenshots/display.png" alt="Artifact Hub screenshots" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When screenshots are made available to Artifact Hub a button will display in the sidebar to access them.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Changelogs</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/changelogs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/changelogs/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/changelogs/changelog.png" alt="changelog" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Changelog">Changelogs&lt;/a> are useful for consumers of an artifact or package. They let consumers see, at a glance, what has changed without needing to read or understand the source. Reading the source doesn&amp;rsquo;t convey intent as well as a changelog, either. To understand intent, you often need to look at issues and commit messages for some additional context. All of that can be summarized in a changelog.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Artifact Hub CLI tool (ah)</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/ah-cli/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/ah-cli/</guid><description>&lt;p>Artifact Hub leverages metadata stored in annotations. This metadata provides details such as the images in use, if something is an operator, and more. Annotations provide an easy way to convey this information. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great to check these annotations before cutting a release? Now you can with the &lt;code>ah&lt;/code> command line tool.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>1.0.0 Released</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/1.0.0-released/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/1.0.0-released/</guid><description>&lt;p>We&amp;rsquo;re happy to announce the release of &lt;a href="https://github.com/artifacthub/hub/releases/tag/v1.0.0">Artifact Hub 1.0.0&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/1.0.0-released/ah.png" alt="Artifact Hub" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Artifact Hub is more than a website where you can search for cloud native packages. The software that powers the Artifact Hub is open source and can be run by anyone.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Embed Artifact Details On Your Site</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/embed-widget/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/embed-widget/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/embed-widget/embed.png" alt="Embedded Packages" />&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever want to show off a package from the Artifact Hub on a website? I know I&amp;rsquo;ve thought about putting one in the sidebar of a website. Artifact Hub now makes that easy with a widget you can embed. The above image displays various configurations of the widget you can get from Artifact Hub.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Verified Publishers and Official Status</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/verified-and-official-repos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/verified-and-official-repos/</guid><description>&lt;p>Ever wonder if you are getting a package for a piece of software from the developer of that software? Or, have you ever wondered if the person who listed a repository or package on the Artifact Hub owns it? If you have, than you&amp;rsquo;re in luck. The Artifact Hub has badges that can answer those questions for you.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Helm Values Schema Reference</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-values-schema-reference/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/helm-values-schema-reference/</guid><description>&lt;p>Helm v3 introduced &lt;a href="https://helm.sh/docs/topics/charts/#schema-files">schemas for values&lt;/a>. The schemas are written as JSON Schemas and put in a chart in a file named &lt;code>values.schema.json&lt;/code> that goes right alongside &lt;code>values.yaml&lt;/code> files. Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be great if there was a way to easily use these files to understand the values in a chart? Artifact Hub provides just that with its Values Schema Reference.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Discover Tekton Tasks</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/discover-tekton-tasks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/discover-tekton-tasks/</guid><description>&lt;p>Artifact Hub has already provided search and discovery for Helm charts, OLM based operators, Falco rules, OPA policies, Tinkerbell actions, Krew (kubectl) plugins, and Helm plugins. These are all &lt;a href="https://www.cncf.io/">CNCF&lt;/a> project related artifacts. We are happy to share that we have expanded beyond the CNCF to support another non-profit foundation based project with support for &lt;a href="https://tekton.dev/">Tekton&lt;/a> tasks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Container Image Scanning</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/container-image-scanning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/container-image-scanning/</guid><description>&lt;p>When trying to make a decision about which artifacts to use it&amp;rsquo;s useful to know some information about the security of the artifact. With Artifact Hub, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to see security scans for container based artifacts such as Operator Framework OLM based operators, some Helm Charts, OPA Policies, and Tinkerbell actions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is The Artifact Hub?</title><link>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/what-is-artifacthub/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 09:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.artifacthub.io/blog/what-is-artifacthub/</guid><description>&lt;p>Finding cloud native artifacts on the Internet can be difficult. When we talk about artifacts we mean things like &lt;a href="https://helm.sh">Helm&lt;/a> charts, Kubernetes operators, &lt;a href="https://falco.org/">Falco&lt;/a> rules, and &lt;a href="https://www.openpolicyagent.org/">Open Policy Agent&lt;/a> (OPA) policies. If you use a search engine to look for them the results will be mixed with articles, documentation, and discussion. This experience is far from ideal if you want to find a package or tool to install.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This has lead to the rise of Hubs like the Helm Hub (which now redirects to the Artifact Hub) and &lt;a href="https://operatorhub.io/">Operator Hub&lt;/a>. These hubs made it possible to discover distributed artifacts for one project or another. These hubs improved the experience but were still missing an opportunity.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>